Okay, some of the advantages.... We're going to prepare this speech ahead of time, word-for-word, prior to committing it to memory, so this will allow us to devote quite a bit of attention to style.
How do we want to write this?
What is the style that we are going to use to memorize, to present this speech?
Also, you can review and eliminate any potential problems that could come up in the future.
We're writing it out word-for-word.
We see ahead of time, "Hey, I can see how this can be misconstrued," or, "Oh, I think people will reject that."
So you can fix it ahead of time where those things are harder to fix when you are on your feet.
Also, by having a speech committed to memory, some of the positives include eye contact.
I'm not having to look at a paper, again, kind of like an impromptu, so I can make really good eye contact and I can also move around.
I have the freedom to gesture without having to have a piece of paper in my hand or a note card, and I can walk around.
I'm not limited to being just behind the podium.
So those are some of the advantages of speaking from memory.